Aashutosh Trivedi

Bengaluru ■ aashutoshtrivedi1@gmail.com □ +91-6360240072 ■ in/aashutosh-trivedi-b61b44103/

SUMMARY

6+ years of professional experience in Product Development, including writing consistently good and maintainable code, serving 11k+ SMBs, with complete automated unit & functional tests. Maintain strongly consistent personal velocity of work tasks and commitment to backend development, delivering high-quality solutions through collaboration, and innovation.

EXPERIENCE

Staff Software Engineer

Trinet Zenefits

April 2023 - Present, Bangalore

- · Led collaboration efforts with external company Noyo Benefits to develop and implement a backend intensive benefits fulfilment lifecycle, utilizing REST APIs for insurance companies Kaiser and Ameritas, resulting in the successful onboarding of 100+ small and medium-sized businesses (SMBs).
- Successfully led a team of 5 in redesigning benefits fulfillment methods, incorporating Custom Lines of Coverage into EDI, Insurance Carrier APIs, and Manual Forms, contributing \$1.5 million ARR on sharing basis with insurance carriers.
- Successfully migrated multiple Django apps from Python 2 to Python 3, resolving syntax issues, implementing future decorators, fixing CI tests and ensuring typecasting, resulting in a 100% compatibility rate with Python.
- Facilitated professional development for team members through mentoring interns and colleagues, Conducted code structure analysis sessions and collaboration meetings, leading to improved approaches and streamlined project delivery timelines.

Senior Software Engineer

Zenefits

July 2021 - April 2023, Bangalore

- Designed backend integration for processing Affordable Care Act forms through the IRS website using SOAP APIs, resulting in successful automation of 700+ forms without any failures, saving 200+ manual hours.
- · Refactored Code for 20+ payroll report types, improving reusability, readability and optimizing report generation by 75%.
- · Implemented UI migration of web app from Ember JS to React JS, optimizing backend APIs and achieving a 100% reduction in page load time.

Full Stack Developer

Zenefits

July 2018 - October 2021, Bangalore

- Spearheaded targeted initiatives leading to an 90% decrease in customer issues by optimizing UI web flows(Ember JS) and backend Django APIs and monitored key metrics to assess the impact of improvements.
- Developed complete compensation management tool from scratch to suggests compensation for employee based on company location, Industry based on collection of multiple market data, with 650+ million data points along with roll up aggregation feature and successfully delivered this time-sensitive project.
- · Devised an ETL pipeline to automatically extract Marketo data regularly, filtering and storing in AWS S3.

AI Cognitive Developer

Wipro Digital

August 2017 - July 2018, Bangalore

- Created a hybrid search solution customized for the Oil and Petroleum domain utilizing IBM Watson, incorporating a Semantic Search Engine in Django. Capable of processing structured and unstructured data, enabling natural language queries for 100+ data fields.
- · Prize Winners in "Shell Rise of AI Hackathon", 2018, held at Hague, Netherlands, resulting in Shell becoming a client for Wipro Digital.

Internship

Tata Cummins

June 2015 - July 2015, Pune

• Utilized Visual Basic scripts to automate programs for new car engine assembly line.

SKILLS

Languages: Python 3, C++, PHP, Javascript

Cloud Services: AWS Database: MySQL Frameworks: Django, Graphql, React JS, IBM Watson, Telegram BOT Others: REST APIs, SOAP APIs

EDUCATION

B. Tech in Computer Science and Engineering

Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore • July 2013 - May 2017 • 8.58

Senior Secondary Education

Gyan Ganga Educational Academy, Raipur · April 2011 - May 2013 · 90.8 %

CERTIFICATIONS

IBM Watson V₃ Application Developer